[♪ legendary music playing]
[lightsaber activates]
[♪ music fades]
[♪ theme music playing]
[narrator] The era of the Jedi
and the Sith has ended.
They have all but disappeared.
and with them. the ancient art
of crafting their sacred weapon.
the lightsaber.
A terrible age of conflict now mires
the galaxy in chaos as warlords rise.
Among them. the fierce masked general.
Nawaam. has emerged.
spreading terror as planets fall under
his control at an alarming rate.
Amid this. Margrave Juro works
to bring back the Jedi Order
in hope that they can restore
peace and justice to the galaxy.
[♪ music concludes]
[♪ thrilling music playing]
[ship whooshes]
[gasps. grunts]
[laser cannons firing]
How are they doing this? They keep finding
us no matter how many times we jump.
There must be a tracker
on the ship somewhere.
They probably put one on us
during our first run-in.
[Kara over comms] What?
[droid chirping]
-[whooshes]
-[laser cannons firing]
[Gennoh] Lord Nawaam. I will soon
have Margrave Juro's ship.
This will be the day
I wipe out his pathetic group
and return with all of their lightsabers.
[Nawaam] Our enemies see themselves
as masterless Jedi.
You'd be wise to not let your guard down.
I. Gennoh. would never
back down from any Jedi.
[Nawaam] Very well.
Then show me the power of the last Sith.
[Gennoh] As you wish.
[explosion]
[alarm blaring]
[whimpers]
[whooshes]
-[thuds]
-[Homen and Juro grunt]
Master. the ship's navicomputer is down.
And what about the backup?
Those are all shot as well.
There's no way we'll be able
to make a jump to hyperspace without them.
Can you repair it. Kara?
[Kara over comms] There's no time.
We won't make it.
All right. Take the controls. Gramps.
Get ready to make the jump
as soon as we get into a better position.
[Gramps] Good grief. Very reckless. kid.
Very reckless.
The coordinates?
[Gramps] I've got all that stuff
up here in my noggin.
-Well. then. where are you taking us?
-[Gramps grumbles]
[Homen grunts]
[♪ thrilling music playing]
[Gennoh] Jump as many times
as you wish. It's still futile.
I have you now.
-[rumbling]
-[grunts]
[gasps]
[distant alarm wailing]
[Kara gasps] Gramps.
are you seeing what I'm seeing?
[Homen] Do something. We're being
pulled right into that black hole.
[Gramps] Relax. A ship this nimble
will be able to make it out easy.
Not sure about that big clunker
behind us. though. [chuckles]
[droid] High gravitational pull detected.
Navigation disabled.
[Gennoh] Of all the petty tricks...
That was quick thinking.
Quite the strategy. Gramps.
Enough compliments.
We need to get out of here now.
[Gramps] Things are about to get
a little bumpy.
[♪ thrilling music continues]
[whooshes]
[Kara grunts]
[screams]
[engines revving]
[whooshing]
Whoo-hoo!
Gramps. you're the best!
[Gramps] That is accurate.
We have escaped the black hole.
Now then.
where shall we jump to next?
Our best course of action
would be to head to Makoma Ko.
Set a course immediately.
[Gramps] All righty.
[whooshes]
-[♪ dramatic music playing]
-[parts clattering]
-[alarm blaring]
-[rumbling]
[droid] We have insufficient thrust.
[Gennoh] I'll handle this.
[ship rumbling]
[straining]
[whooshes]
[♪ serene music playing]
[ship engine whirring]
[Kara] So this is Makoma Ko.
[Juro] It's ruled by a man named Dunbai.
He was a Jedi a long time ago.
A Jedi. that's a surprise.
Dunbai is well known.
He's one of the wealthiest merchants
in the Outer Rim.
Hard to imagine he was once a Jedi.
Hmm. Then I really hope
he'll be able to help us.
[♪ valiant music playing]
[ship hisses]
[alien speaking alien language]
-[indistinct conversations]
-[droid warbles]
[♪ enthralling music playing]
[birds chirping]
[droid chirps]
[grunts]
Apologies. Margrave. but I'm afraid I will
be unable to lend you any assistance.
Lord Dunbai. do you mean to say
that you will allow the galaxy
to continue to fall into chaos?
My primary duty must be
to protect my home. Makoma Ko.
My hands are full enough with that.
-[Dunbai grunts]
-[gasps]
Hmm. What's this?
It is a saber forged by Lah Zhima.
I ask you again. will you take this up
and fight once more as a Jedi?
[Dunbai] You will never be able
to bring back the Jedi Order
with such a paltry number.
And furthermore.
there is no master among you.
[grunts] You're wrong. We do have
a master. and his name is Margrave Juro.
[whimpers]
If you have the strength
to stand up against Nawaam.
I have no doubt others will follow.
This is an opportunity to provide them
with a beacon of hope.
-[Dunbai] Hmm.
-[droid warbles]
[Dunbai] That may be.
However. blindly gathering others
won't bring the Jedi back.
I can only hope that you will
not find yourselves crushed
if you insist on pursuing
this fool-hearted quest.
Although I seriously doubt
this Nawaam would be the one to do it.
You should not underestimate Nawaam.
As we speak. he is busy amassing a fleet.
and soon it will be
the biggest in the galaxy.
His Nobuseri fighters are a problem.
A throng of brutes
who have never bent the knee to anyone
now swear allegiance to him.
What do you imagine
he may have promised them in return?
Nawaam's danger lies at the heart
of what that may be.
Hmm.
[Kara] I thought you said
Dunbai used to be a Jedi.
Seems he's no more
than a greedy merchant now.
Does this mean that he really
isn't going to help us?
[Homen and Kara grunt]
Who is this girl with you?
Lah Kara. She is Zhima's daughter.
[gasps]
So then he survived?
Yes. But he was abducted.
likely on Nawaam's orders.
So you are traveling with Margrave Juro
in search of your father. is that correct?
How brave of you.
We need your help.
Please lend us your aid.
I fear. without it.
I won't be able to find my father.
I'm sorry.
but as I have already explained.
what matters most to me
is protecting this planet and its people.
And so I cannot help you.
But you're not safe just sitting idly by.
I thought that once.
Until one day they came
and took what matters most.
[gasps]
I'm sorry. I should not have
spoken to you that way.
I apologize for speaking like that.
Margrave Juro.
It's quite all right.
You have expressed my sentiments exactly.
Although there is one thing. Kara.
you can just call me Juro. remember?
Yes. Juro.
-[building rumbling]
-[all gasp]
[attendant panting]
[whispers indistinctly]
It appears you and your friends
have brought trouble to our door.
[Juro] Hmm?
[♪ tense music playing]
[Gennoh] Did you think you could get away
from me with that little stunt?
How naive of you. Jedi.
[whirring]
[gasps] How'd they find us?
I thought we destroyed the tracker.
[Homen] We did destroy it.
When we arrived at the spaceport.
-[indistinct droid chatter]
-[all exclaim]
I wonder how he managed to escape
the gravitational pull of the black hole.
Unfortunate. but very impressive.
[both] Can you please stop praising him?
Excuse me. sir. we are receiving
an incoming transmission.
It is from Nawaam's army.
[whirring]
I am Commander Gennoh of Nawaam's army.
We have been informed that you are
harboring these seditious Jedi.
and we demand
that you hand them over to us.
Well. I'm afraid
I have received no reports
of any such Jedi hiding on this planet.
Isn't that right?
[Gennoh] Have you no shame?
But even if they were here.
I would not be duty-bound
to turn them over to your custody.
Might I remind you
that Makoma Ko are a free city-state.
As such. we are not under
the control of the Nawaam army.
And in terms of rival warlords
we may be bound to. there are none.
[Gennoh] You wretched cur.
Do you intend to defy General Nawaam?
And what is it that you intend?
Perhaps you intend to violate
the autonomy of Makoma Ko.
Is he doing what I think he's doing?
'Cause it looks like he's helping us.
-No matter how stubborn Dunbai may be...
-[Kara] Hmm?
[Juro] ...he is a man of high principle.
[Gennoh] Very well. in that case.
you shall die alongside your Jedi friends.
[warbles]
Bring the ground troops down.
burn the whole city
and smoke out the Jedi.
And do not forget
to take their lightsabers.
[droid whirring]
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[citizens exclaiming]
[citizen 1] What is that?
-[citizen 2] Here they come.
-[citizen 3] Oh. they're coming down!
[citizen 4] They're landing!
[panicked screaming]
[thuds]
[♪ sinister music playing]
[ships decelerate]
[guard] Ready? Lure them closer.
[blasters firing]
-[explosion]
-[guards screaming]
[guards gasping. whimpering]
[guards groaning]
[panting]
[Homen panting]
-[Kara grunts]
-[Homen sighs]
This does not look good.
They're attacking everyone
and everything in sight.
-[Kara grunts]
-[Homen gasps]
[Kara] This is horrible.
-[gasps] Hold on. do you see our ship?
-[gasps]
[Gramps] The ship's hidden.
You're welcome.
Shall I come get you?
Yeah. but be careful. okay?
Even though we're outnumbered.
these droids are controlled
by a central command unit.
If you take that out. they'll become
nothing more than training dummies.
Wait. Are you seriously proposing that we
directly infiltrate the enemy's ship?
Have you lost your mind?
The element of surprise
is a basic principle of warfare.
Wouldn't you agree?
"It is better to take the right path
than the straight one."
Don't worry. I haven't forgotten the basic
principles of the Jedi's teachings.
[Juro grunts softly]
[panting]
Hey. Gramps is here.
Are you really planning
on attempting this alone?
As you said.
your role is to protect your city.
and in doing so. you will
be attracting the enemy's attention.
-[droid warbles]
-[Dunbai] Hmm?
[Juro] You'll need it at a time like this.
So keep it.
[Dunbai] Are you taking
that child with you?
[Kara panting]
I told you already.
She's not just any girl.
She's the daughter of Lah Zhima.
Thank you for all your help.
You have nothing to worry about.
We won't be reckless.
[Kara panting]
Hmm. [inhales]
-[♪ tense music playing]
-[distant explosions]
We have to get out of this system. now.
It doesn't matter where to.
[whooshes]
[Kara] Where are we?
We're approximately five parsecs
from Makoma Ko right now.
If we jump back there right now.
how close to the target
will we be able to get?
[Gramps] Oh. my!
You are proving to be just as reckless
-as young Kara here. sir.
-[Kara chuckles]
[whooshes]
[engine revving]
[♪ dramatic music playing]
Gramps. we're gonna crash!
[engine roaring]
-[Gramps] You were saying?
-[sighs]
Impressive flying.
Our sole objective
is that central droid control unit.
[droid] The enemy has infiltrated.
Combat has been detected
on the third deck.
[Gennoh] Their petty tricks
just keep on coming.
-[blasters firing]
-[guards grunting]
[guards screaming. grunting]
[gasping]
[Dunbai grunts]
[gasps] Lord Dunbai.
Come with me.
Sir.
[blasters firing]
[guard grunts]
[guards groaning]
[Dunbai grunting]
[guard gasps]
[straining. panting]
[electronic beeping]
Hmm. Ah!
There. That path leads directly
to the droid control center.
-[lightsaber crackling]
-[metal thuds]
Don't be reckless.
[Kara] I know.
[mechanical whirring]
[grunting. panting]
[Gennoh] And what business might you have
in this room. little mouse?
[Kara gasps]
Identify yourself.
Are you the one in charge of this vessel?
I am Gennoh Ikagi.
The commander of Nawaam's army.
Now you would do well to go to your death
with honor and at my hand.
[lightsaber buzzing]
[gasps] That's a lightsaber.
How do you have one of those?
Nobody but my father can craft them.
[Gennoh] Your father?
Then you are Lah Zhima's daughter?
How do you know who my father is?
[Gennoh] He is one of the General's
closest collaborators.
And he has been very cordially received.
What are you saying?
-[whooshes]
-[Kara gasps]
-[lightsaber crackling]
-[Kara grunts]
[lightsaber buzzing]
[♪ tense music playing]
[lightsabers buzzing]
[Kara grunting]
[lightsaber crackling]
[Kara panting. grunts]
[lightsaber buzzing]
[lightsaber crackling]
-[thuds]
-[Kara grunts]
-[lightsabers crackling]
-[Kara straining]
[Kara screams. grunts]
[gasps]
-[lightsaber crackling]
-[Kara gasps]
[sizzling]
[Kara panting]
[Gennoh] You did well for a girl so young.
but this is the end.
[Kara grunts]
-I think I kept you busy long enough.
-[Gennoh] What?
I just needed to keep you distracted
so that my friend over there
could stop your droids.
[Gennoh gasps]
-[electricity crackling]
-[explosion]
[droids powering down]
[both gasp. chuckle]
[Dunbai gasps. sighs]
[droids powering down]
[rumbling]
-[metallic creaking]
-[droids thud]
[♪ dramatic music playing]
-[Kara gasps]
-[Gennoh grunts]
[Kara] What was that? [gasps]
[Gennoh] With the droids deactivated.
there's nobody to fly the ship.
Or did you not account for that?
Huh?
[Gennoh] Tell me. what's your name. girl?
-Kara.
-[Gennoh] Hmm.
Lah Kara.
[Gennoh] I will remember that
for the next time we meet.
[gasps]
Huh?
[crashing]
[citizens exclaiming]
[citizens laughing]
I can't believe
those guys actually pulled it off.
Quite impressive indeed.
[♪ pensive music playing]
[whooshes]
[indistinct chatter]
[alien chittering]
-[alien chittering]
-[Homen gasps] Hmm?
[indistinct chatter]
[sighs]
[Gennoh] He is one of the General's
closest collaborators.
And he has been very cordially received.
[Kara] Father...
collaborating with Nawaam?
That's impossible.
He would never
willingly work with men like him.
Never.
[♪ melancholy music playing]
They may be gone for now.
but this won't be the last we see of them.
[Dunbai] Ah. but you forget.
Makoma Ko is a free city-state
and we will yield to no one.
[Juro] You're as stubborn as ever.
[Dunbai] I could say the same of you.
[grunts softly] Thanks for this.
However. I left behind
the Jedi life long ago.
You're even more stubborn than I thought.
[sighs]
You don't have to go back to being a Jedi.
but I'm not taking that back either.
Keep it and use it
to protect the people of this planet.
[Dunbai] Hmm.
[ships whooshing]
[♪ tense music playing]
[droid] Emergency transmission
from Gennoh.
Juro's group has struck down his ship.
Evacuation underway.
[Nawaam sighs] That Margrave Juro
is formidable.
[droid] There is more.
Zhima's daughter is accompanying them.
She is attuned to the Force
and not to be underestimated.
[Nawaam] Lord Zhima. did you take
your daughter as your Padawan?
She is the daughter
of a sabersmith after all.
It's only natural
that she's picked up a few things.
[Nawaam] You toy with me
at your own peril.
Look at you.
one of the strongest of all the Jedi.
yet you still insist on calling yourself
a mere sabersmith?
[indistinct chatter]
[Four-Nines speaking Binary]
[in English] What?
Of course I'm not scared.
I... I volunteered to do this after all.
You're sure about this?
This mission will be a dangerous one.
I'm sure. Just leave it to me.
[Four-Nines speaking Binary]
[in English] It's okay. He'll have backup.
Four-Nines will be there to help
if anything goes wrong.
-[Four-Nines speaking Binary]
-[Ethan gasps]
[chuckles]
[indistinct chatter]
[Ethan in English] So is this general
really as great as everyone claims?
[man] Hmm?
We'll know soon enough.
[Ethan] Does anyone else
think it's strange
that we all follow a guy
we don't know anything about?
I heard that if anyone can beat him.
he promised to give them
control of his army.
Do we really think
he's serious about that?
Why are you bringing that up?
[stutters] I was just curious. that's all.
-[Nawaam] I am serious.
-[all gasp]
[♪ tense music playing]
[people murmuring]
[people exclaim]
[Nawaam] I do not request your loyalty.
If any of you can kill me.
you may become general in my stead.
However. until that happens.
I am in command
and you will follow my orders.
That is the deal.
Did you want to challenge me?
-How about you. masterless Jedi?
-[gasps]
-[people murmuring]
-I have no idea what you're talking about.
[Nawaam] You came to investigate my army.
did you not?
Did you think you would go unnoticed?
-[Ethan panting]
-[Four-Nines speaking Binary]
[Ethan] Uh...
[in English] That's a good point. Yeah.
Juro's been looking for masterless Jedi
and there's a chance
that he could be one of them.
Hey. you. You a spy or something?
You know. I bet he thinks
he's better than us.
[growls. grunts]
-[all exclaim]
-[grunts]
[man grunting]
Huh. Not half bad.
[Nawaam] Agreed. You are quite skilled.
However. with no lightsaber.
I suppose that spear
is a more suitable weapon than a blaster.
I had really hoped
that it would not need to come to this.
However. there's no point anymore.
-[spear slashes]
-This is a great opportunity.
Now I can simply fight you.
[Nawaam] Tell me your name.
I will not give my name to a tyrant.
[Nawaam chuckles] How noble of you.
[lightsaber buzzing]
-[gasps]
-[grunts]
-[clangs]
-[Nawaam grunts]
[♪ dramatic music playing]
-[man grunts]
-[spear clangs]
[Ethan gasps]
It's blue.
Is Nawaam a Jedi?
How?
[♪ dramatic music swells. ends]
[♪ theme music playing]
[♪ music ends]